# Sahil Johari

Pittsburgh PA 15219 | 214-458-7161 | sahiljohari12@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Offering over **2.5 years of experience** in software engineering. Currently **working as a Front-end Software Engineer** in an agile environment and creating some exciting and rewarding user interfaces for next-generation web apps using modern frameworks.

- Key Competencies -

Communication | Attention to Detail | Teamwork | Creativity | Passion | Quick Learning | Curiosity | Ownership

### **Technical Skills**

- Web Standards: HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript
- Front end Frameworks: React, Redux, Node, TypeScript
- Testing Frameworks: Cypress, Jest, Enzyme, rspec-rails
- Programming Languages: Python, MySQL
- Others: REST API consumption, Git/GitHub, CI/CD, Test-driven development

#### **Professional Experience**

**Software Engineer – Rivers Agile | IBM** – Pittsburgh, PA

August 2019 - Present

**Technologies Used:** React, Redux, TypeScript, Node, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress

- Develop using wireframes the front-end UI of Discovery Tooling a user facing online tool in IBM Watson™ Discovery, with 48 user stories completed so far
- Collaborate with other developers from front-end, back-end, and UI/UX designers to create product features
- Successfully completed and deployed over 18 user stories/features for product release in November 2019
- Developed and owned the conversational feature (**Chat Bot**) which uses Discovery API to provide intuitive responses to user queries
- Contributed significantly in migrating over 30 integration tests from *rspec-rails* to *Cypress* framework to improve testability, maintainability, and code readability

#### Senior Analyst - Capgemini Technology Services India Limited - India

June 2015 - June 2017

Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, ¡Query, ASP.NET, C#, Oracle PL-SQL

- Reduced the lead time by 80% (as reported) for the customer via generating and distributing over 125 reports by developing an automation web application using .NET framework
- Redesigned and implemented UI for a legacy application to offer improved aesthetics and user experience using jQuery and Bootstrap
- Independently analyzed and validated program specifications as well as developed reliable and reusable C# code

#### Education

**Master of Science, Computer Science** 

May 2019 GPA: 3.53/4.0

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas

Bachelor of Engineering, Information Technology

June 2015

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

**GPA: 70.13% (Final Year)** 

# **Additional Experience**

# **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

January 2019 - April 2019

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Southern Methodist University - Dallas, Texas

- Course: Principles of Computer Science
- Instructed undergraduate students on hands-on programming sessions in Java conducted for a span of 8 weeks

#### **Projects**

• Messenger App | React, Node, Socket-IO

May 2020 - Present

Game for Intelligent Simulated Military Opponents (Academic) | TensorFlow.js, p5.js

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

Snake using Deep Reinforcement Learning (Academic) | Python, TensorFlow, Keras

Jun 2018 – Aug 2018